キルア あんたのおかげよ。
Fearsome monsters... Exotic creatures...
起きてから　ずっと　そうだった。
Vast riches... Hidden treasures...
自分が無力だなんて思わないで。
Evil enclaves... Unexplored lands...
私がゴンのため
The word "unknown" holds magic.
何かできるなら喜んでする。
And some incredible people are
drawn to that magic.
でも　忘れないで。
They are known...
ゴンに 一番必要なのは　あなたなのよ。
...as Hunters!
ゴンを思うキルアの言葉が
Reply x From x Dad
奇跡的に パームを元の姿に戻した
The box that had been sealed with Nen
その頃　西塔の２階では メレオロンの 再三の制止を振り切り
contained three mysterious items. One of them, an old cassette tape, gave Gon his first chance
プフとの 直接対決に臨んだナックルが
to hear his father's voice.
彼らの前に姿を現していた
Yo, Gon...
プフ。
This is my dad's voice.
表　出ろや。
If you do, keep on listening.
ですが　その前に まず言っておきましょう。
I'm guessing that's a "yes."
ここにいる私は　いわば分身。
Then I'll ask you once more. Are you prepared?
本体は　すでに 王の元へと向かっています。
Hunters are selfish creatures.
自身が　煙の檻から脱出した後
If you're only slightly interested in seeing me, you should stop the tape now. I'll give you a minute to consider it.
ナックルとモラウが 接触していることを
Well?
分身のことは　ボスから聞いてる。
I guess you really do want to see me.
事実だ。
But I don't want to see you.
ナックルが口にしたのは ゴンに伝えるためである
I don't know how I could face you now. After all, I chose my own desires
先に真実を述べることで
over my parental duty.
心理的に先手を打つ
I'm a bad person.
だが　なぜ自分から言い出す？ プフの目的は　ユピーにあった
I'm guessing that by the time
you hear this tape, at least ten years will have passed.
ナックルが　ここにいる以上 ユピーは 彼を見逃したことになり
But one thing still hasn't changed.
理由によっては…
I'm still me.
プフは ユピーに感じた変化の真意を
As you listen to this tape, I'm off doing reckless things.
ナックルから探るため
If you want to see me, find me.
この場を 穏便に離れる必要があったのだ
But as I said before, I don't want to see you.
まず　彼を納得させるため。
If I sense you nearby,
I'll make myself scarce.
彼は　私がこの場から動かないよう 要求しています。
Catch me if you can.
１対１の勝負なら 場所を変えるため
You are a Hunter, aren't you?
私は分身。
Your dad isn't gonna be easy to track.
鱗粉も使いません。
Oh, wait...
それでもよろしければ お相手します。
Ging's still there. Oh, I forgot to mention something...
それ故の告白です。
It's about your mother.
背後から　わざわざ声を掛け
If you want to know more, keep listening. If you're not interested...
１対１の戦いを望む人間には
Are you sure?
正直に話していると 見せることが効果的だと プフは知っていた
Yeah. But he might have left you a clue. I doubt it.
ウソをつけ。
Besides, I already told you... My mom is Mito-san.
お前は　さっき 俺を後ろから殺そうとした。
I see.
自分でも　そう言った。
Are you hungry? I'll go grab something.
ナックル　だまされるな。
Yeah.
まず お前が本体でなく分身だって？
Hey, Gon!
その証拠が　どこにある？
The tape started moving all by itself! What?!
くっ！
There's aura around the tape player!
確かに
It's Nen...
Nen is rewinding the cassette!
こいつ　厄介だ
No, he infused this player with
Nen over ten years ago! So it would start rewinding,
once it was stopped! Why?
恐らく　敵の中で一番
Beats me.
こいつが 揺るがぬ意志を持っている
Now it's recording! I get it! He's erasing his message!
彼が　ピトーと共に 縛られている現状は
What? It's not working! I can't stop it...
むしろ 歓迎すべきなのかもしれません
Damn!
なぜなら彼は
It still won't stop! I pulled the plug!
揺るがぬ意志で　ここにいるから
Sorry, Gon. I'll have to break it!
私が本体かどうかを 証明するのは 私自身をすこぶる不利にするので 言えませんね。
Damn! No good! There's Nen protecting the player!
この後　どうするかは あなたにお任せします。
It's finished.
やめろ。
Now it's recording! I get it! He's erasing his message!
ハハハハ…！
I'm guessing he didn't want to leave any clues.
アハハハ…！
Clues?
アハハハ…！　ハハハハ…！
You can extract a lot of information
from an audio clip. Really?
ハハハハ…！ アハハハ…！　ハハハハ…！
You can determine the
speaker's height, weight, gender, age, facial features, chronic diseases, and state of mind.
アハハハ…！
From the background noise,
you can also determine the location.
来るか来ないかは　あなた次第！
But he was more worried
about something else.
くっ…。
Nen.
プフのことは謝る！ 僕がいればいいだろ？
I wouldn't be surprised if
there were a Nen user somewhere who could analyze
data better than a machine.
１０分。
Oh, I get it.
えっ？ 予定より１０分早く　治せ。
Your dad's a tough nut. Since the tape's useless now, we only have two clues left...
ピトーは　戦慄していた
The ring and the memory card.
この場が どうなろうと構わないと
I doubt the ring will help, but the memory card could be important.
プフが判断し　離れたことにも 少なからず動揺したが
Yeah, it's smaller than a normal memory card. Maybe you need a special machine to use it?
それ以上に プフの挑発を意に介さず
Huh? You can't tell?
時間の短縮を告げた ゴンを恐れた
This memory card only works with the JS. The JS? A gaming console called the JoyStation.
((時間は？ どれだけ待てばいい？))
You don't know anything, do you? If this island still has tape players,
it probably has a console.
((完全に回復させるには
Is there a toy store here? Yeah, there is.
３４時間は　かかると思う))
Okay, hold on.
((１時間あれば…
Oh, where are you going? The toy store.
重大な危機を 乗り切れるところまでは治せる))
It's outside the port! Got it!
当初　コムギを守り 完治させたい一心から
Have a safe trip!
実は ピトーがコムギの状態を見て
So this is a JoyStation...
完治にかかると 踏んだ時間だった
This brings back memories.
しかし　幾度かの経験で
I used to play with these all the time. There were a bunch of hidden
gems for this console.
「ドクターブライス」の技術は 成長していた
Then is this memory card
one of those hidden gems?
治療しながら　１０分は 早められるかもしれない
I don't see a title anywhere. You've never played any video games, have you?
そう思っていた矢先であった
That's unusual. Really? That isn't a game disc.
偶然かもしれない
It holds a game's memory data.
プフの去り際のセリフに
So you can't use it to play.
ゴンが同調しただけの 可能性が高い
Yeah, you're supposed to
put the disc in here.
そう思いながら　ピトーは 不吉な思いを振り払えずにいた 命懸けになる
But if you insert the memory card and
power it on without a game inside, you can see which games are using that memory. Oh, really...
でないと　こいつの牙は…
It looks like there's only one game saved on it.
王の喉元にも 届き得るかもしれない！
It's called Greed Island. Greed Island?
分かった。
Anyway, there are a bunch of saves.
ナックル。 おっ。
I doubt it will do any good,
but I'll copy the data just in case.
ここは　俺１人で大丈夫。 さっきは　ああ言ったけど
Copying Greed Island. Okay.
プフの本体が王の所へ 向かったっていうのは
What are you doing?
本当だと思う。
Searching on-line.
南だよ　王は。
We know the game's name. So I'm looking for a store that sells it.
ゴンは　キルアと共に その現場に居合わせた
There aren't any used copies... An out-of-print game would still have
some used copies floating around.
それを知らないピトーが プフとのたくらみを
It's possible that this game isn't for sale.
看破されていたのだと 判断したのは
What do you mean? It could be an indie game
思考の流れとして当然であった もうろうとした恐れが 確信に変わった瞬間である
that was never for sale or was
banned for some reason.
ピトーは 自らの使命を完全に覚悟した
Anyway, I'll keep searching. There we go. This game was sold through
legitimate channels.
殺さねばならない
And what's with that price tag?!
何としても
Five hundred, eighty million?
こいつを
It's five billion, eight hundred million! Huh?
王のために！
That's ridiculous!
いや　ダメだ 彼女を危険にさらせない
That isn't very many. It's practically nothing! The developers were cocky... The number is way too low!
まず 治した彼女を誰に任せる？
But it makes sense. The price is ridiculous,
but Hunters can afford it.
プフもユピーも コムギを煙たがっている
That explains how they sold out. Do the makers have any left in stock?
ダメだ
Yeah, I guess we could ask.
僕がいなくなったら 誰がコムギを王へ？
The game you are inquiring about
is no longer in stock.
ゴン。 おめぇの言いたいことは理解した。
Unfortunately, there are no plans
to print additional copies.
その上で　俺は俺のやり方でやる。
I see, thanks. That's a no-go.
ユピーは…。
I guess we'll have to find someone with
a copy and ask them to let us have it. Yeah, our best bet is to advertise
on a reverse auction website
いや　何でもねえ。
If we pool our money from the arena, that's eight hundred million.
自らの情報で ゴンに動揺や迷いが生じたら
Then we need another five billion... Not necessarily.
それが結果　死を招くこともある じゃあな。
Huh? With these private deals,
the seller holds all the power. Typically, they'll ask for more
than the original price.
辛うじて ナックルは思いとどまった
So it'll cost even more? Maybe.
なぜ　貴様が 余の名前を知っている？
Price negotiable."
部下が　お主の 母親の臨終に立ち会ったのよ。
Wh-What?
いまわの言葉が お主の名だったそうだ。
We already have over ten thousand hits! So that's it...
その部下も護衛軍との戦闘で 死んでしまったかもな。
They're trying to foist counterfeits off on us. That should have been obvious,
considering the price. This plan is a wash.
やる気になったかね？
Besides, we can't even tell
if it's the real game.
わしに負けを 認めさすことができれば
If we dig more deeply on-line,
we might uncover more information.
教えてやらんでもないぞ？
But I'm not too familiar with that stuff.
殺さず　気の済むまでか…。
Is there anyone who knows a bunch
about games and the Net? Oh, there's someone who
knows a lot about both.
「飛車角落ち」 といったところだな。
He might even own a copy of Greed Island. What? Really?
まぁ　すぐに詰んでやろう。
Gotoh-san?
王が応じると同時
What? Killua wants to talk to me?
ネテロは飛んだ
Screw that! Tell him I'm not here.
いつからだ
I'm busy here. Greed Island ?
敵の攻撃を 待つようになったのは
I never expected you to ask me
about a super-rare game. You don't own a copy?
) )
No, I don't. I wanted one, but I was five
when the game went on sale.
)
So I didn't have any money.
There were over twenty thousand
requests for a hundred copies.
)
Even though each copy cost five billion,
eight hundred million Jenny in cash.
)
I tried looking around later, but I couldn't even find an owner. It's a legendary game for all kinds of reasons.
It's impossible. Forget it. Even I had to give up.
)
Oh? You gave up because it was
beyond your ability?
一体　いつからだ
Sorry. I ended up trading the copy
of the memory card.
差し出して来る両の手に
First, there's a website for Hunters, only accessible by Hunters.
間を置かずに 応えられるようになったのは
We can probably find leads
on Greed Island there. Really?
そんなんじゃねえだろ!!
I'll have to use my Hunter License. Stupid!
俺が求めた武の極みは!!
If you use your home computer,
they'll know your address! You'll have bad guys who want your
license showing up on the island!
敗色濃い難敵にこそ 全霊をもって臨むこと!!
Well, I still don't know the address. My brother promised to tell me,
once he's received the memory card. The second lead is the auction
in Yorknew City.
ここは墓場。
I'm going to end this legend...
貴様のな。
Wow... There's so much food!
感謝するぜ
Ging told Gon to find him,
leaving behind a riddle.
お前と出会えた これまでの全てに！
In order to solve that riddle
and meet his father, Gon leaves his home again and heads
to Yorknew City with Killua.